Most people don't know how bicycles actually work.
大多数人并不知道自行车的运转原理是什么
- Let's try it again.
-我们再试一次
So we modified this bike to prove it.
所以我们改装出这辆自行车来证实它
This video was sponsored by KiwiCo.
（广告不翻译）
More about them at the end of the show.
- When you're riding a bike and you want to turn left,
当你在骑行中想要左转时
I think most people just imagine
我认为大多数人想的都是
you turn the handlebars to the left.
将车把手向左转就可以了
This is a bike to test whether that is true.
这辆自行车就是用来检验这种猜想是否正确
And it's made by my friend Rick here.
它由我的朋友Rick制作
and he's got a radio controller that allows him
他手里拿的这个遥控器
to lock out the steering to one side.
可以锁住车把只能朝一个方向转
So, what he's gonna do is as I'm biking,
当我骑这辆车的时候 Rick要做的是
he's gonna pick whether I can turn
决定我可以往哪儿转
either to the left or to the right.
向左或者向右
So, go for it.
我们开始吧
- I'm giving it a left turn.
-现在我给他一个可以左转的命令
It pulls the pin out,
栓被拉出
but you can see that you can still fully steer
但你现在仍可以随意转动车把
after I've pulled the pin out.
当我将栓完全拉出
I've armed it.
我打开了它的保险
There's where it locks. - OK
这就意味着它锁上了  -好的
Now, that that's when your LED comes on
现在LED亮了
and that just says turn that way.
意味着朝这个方向转弯
- Turn left. - Yeah
-左转  -没错
And if I try to turn right, I can't.
如果我尝试右转的话 我做不到
And if I try to turn left-
如果我尝试左转的话
- You can.
-你可以
- I can.
-我可以
So the question is
问题在于
can I successfully execute this left-hand turn?
我能否成功的执行左转的命令
Should we give it a shot?
我们要试试吗
I mean, he's not gonna tell me whether it's left or right,
Rick不会直接告诉我左转还是右转
so I have to look at the LED to know
所以我只能通过看LED来确认
which way I can still turn.
我可以朝哪个方向转弯
- You let me know when you're ready.
-你准备好了示意我
- Okay.
-好的。
No!
不
That was meant to be a turn to the right
刚才那应该是一个右转
but there was no chance in hell.
但没有机会了
Left.
左转
Right.
右转
All right.
好吧
Right, right, right!
右转 右转 右转
God!
淦
- If you look closely, you can see the problem.
-仔细看的话可以发现问题所在
Here, I'm trying to turn right
在这我尝试右转
but steering that way puts me off balance.
但那样转向会让我失去平衡
If you could ride this bicycle,
当你骑上这辆车时
you would find it's impossible to turn left
你就会发现如果不先右转的话
without first steering right
根本不可能左转
and it's impossible to turn right
同样如果不先左转的话
without first steering left.
根本不可能右转
This seems wrong.
看起来这是错的
I think most people believe you turn a bike
我想大多数人都相信转弯时
simply by pointing the handlebars
只需要简单的将把手
in the direction you want to go.
转向想要转的方向就可以
After all, this is how you drive a car.
毕竟 我们是这样开车的
Point the front wheels any direction you like
将前轮朝向任何你想朝的方向
and the car just goes that way.
车就会朝那个方向行驶
But the difference with a bicycle
而自行车与之不同
is steering doesn't just affect the direction you're headed;
不能做到车把朝哪转 车就往哪拐
it also affects your balance.
转动车把也会影响你的平衡
Imagine you want to make a right turn
想象一下你要右转弯
so you steer the handlebars to the right.
所以你将车把朝右转
What you've done is effectively
这样做会立即
steered the bike out from under you.
使你失去平衡
So now you're leaning to the left
所以你现在朝左倾斜
and the ground puts a force on the bike to the left
同时地面会给车子向左的支撑力
so the only way not to fall
避免摔倒的唯一方式
is to steer the bike to the left.
就是向左转
You have made a left turn.
你完成了一次左转
If you really wanted to turn right,
如果你真的要右转
you first have to counter-steer to the left
你首先要左转
so you can lean right into the turn.
这样你才可以向右倾斜完成转向
This is something anyone who rides a bike knows intuitively
所有人在骑车时都会靠直觉做到这点
but not explicitly.
但自己意识不到
- Turn left!
-左转
- Film someone riding a bike towards you and
-拍摄他人朝你骑行的镜头
tell them which direction to turn
并告诉他们朝哪个方向转向
and you will find that
你就会发现
they counter-steer without even thinking about it.
他们不假思索地就会先将车把朝反方向转
- Hard left!
-向左急转弯
When you're riding a bike,
你骑单车的时候
it's exactly the same as what we call an inverted pendulum
其原理完全符合我们所说的“倒单摆”
or balancing a broomstick on your hand.
也就是在手面上倒立扫帚
If I'm balancing it and I just start walking toward you,
我平衡好之后  如果我开始朝你走去
it will always fall away from you.
扫帚反而会倒向我
If I want to walk towards you, it's easy enough to do
如果我想朝你走去  正确做法不难
and people inherently know how to do it.
人们天生、无意识地就能做到
If I pull it backward, I can now start walking that way.
我先往后拉  就能开始往前走了
I have to initiate the lean to turn into it.
我先要制造前倾  才能在向前走的时候动态保持住
- If you want to move the pendulum somewhere,
如果你想把倒单摆往某个方向移动
you first move the base in the opposite direction.
就先得把底下的支点  往相反方向移动
And now the pendulum is leaning
倒单摆朝你想去的方向倾斜了
in the direction you want to go
so you can move with it.
你就能朝着这个方向走了
And it's the same with a unicycle.
独轮车的原理类似
In order to go forward,
你要想往前走
first, you have to peddle back.
就要先把踏板往回踩
So, you're leaning forward
于是  你的重心往前倾斜
and then you can go forward with it.
你才能向前移动
- Everything you're doing on a unicycle
你在做独轮车上做的一切
is all about keeping that contact patch
都是要把轮胎与地面的接触面
right where it needs to be relative to you.
维持在你想去的方向的前面
You're balancing the broomstick.
跟立扫帚差不多
It's just that on a unicycle,
只不过在独轮车上
you do the longitudinal balance with the pedals
你要维持纵向的平衡  需要借助踏板
and you do the lateral balance, the side to side,
而维持侧向的平衡时
the same as you do with a bike.
就跟骑单车一样了
You essentially- sorta, small counter-steer to get that weight,
你也是先要略往反方向转  让重心往正确的方向移动
to get the contact patch out,
让接触面移过去
and then you can pedal and bring it under you.
你才能踩踏板带着它走
- Now I should point out
我得指出一点
that sometimes when the steering locked,
转向装置被锁住的时候
we just happened to be leaning in the right direction
我的重心可能正好倾斜向右
to execute the turn.
于是我就能完成转向了
- Oh, managed it!
喔  成了
- Essentially by sheer luck,
只要比较欧皇
we had counter-steered
在把手锁住某一边时  重心刚调过去
before that side of the handlebars locked out.
Now, I can keep going.
我就可以不摔下来
- [Rick] Yeah, but don't turn left
但别转左喔
or you're gonna be screwed.
不然你会——的
- I can't turn left.
我没法转左
What's interesting about this is
有意思的地方在于
it shows that you can still ride the bike perfectly well, right?
这样的自行车  居然也能骑得稳当
It's just you can't turn left.
只是没法转左
The funny thing is that you couldn't initiate the turn.
好玩的是  你自己是没法转弯的
I mean, the wild takeaway is that
steering is not just for turning the bike;
转向装置不只是用来转弯的
steering is for balancing.
还是用来维持平衡的
- That's exactly right.
一点儿没错
- Why is it hard to balance on a stationary bike?
为什么我们难以定在静止的自行车上
I think most people believe
我猜大多数人会以为
it's because the wheels aren't spinning
这是因为轮子不转
so there's no gyroscopic effect,
因而没有陀螺仪效应
but that's not it.
事实并非如此
The truth is you use steering
to keep the bike underneath you
but steering doesn't work when you're stationary.
Your balance comes not so much
from how you position your body over the bike,
but by how you steer the bike to keep it underneath you.
Even when going straight,
you're constantly making small steering adjustments
to maintain balance.
- You're moving the contact patch
of the front wheel under you.
You're doing exactly what you do
when you balance a broomstick on your hand.
- So, if the rider is responsible
for steering the bike to keep it balanced,
how do bikes without riders stay upright?
As long as a bike is moving with sufficient speed,
it can keep coasting indefinitely.
I first became aware of this phenomenon
through the great videos by MinutePhysics,
which inspired me to make this video.
You should definitely check them out.
But it turned out the ground
where we went to test this effect was really bumpy,
but the bike still manages to absorb all these perturbations
and remain stable.
So, how does it do this?
I think most people believe it's the wheels spinning
that creates some sort of gyroscopic effect
that resists falling over
just like in this demonstration of gyroscopic precession.
Yhe wheel stays upright
even though gravity is pulling it down.
But this is not why bikes are stable.
Just watch what happens
when we lock the handlebars completely
so you can only go straight ahead.
- Locked out, locked out.
Whoa!
- All that is happening is the steering is locked.
You just got to ride it.
You don't have to turn.
You just ride.
Letting go.
- Some people tried going really fast.
Others experimented with extreme balancing techniques.
- He's leaning. Don't go too fast!
- But even with the gyroscopic
effect of the wheels,
no one was able to keep the bike upright
for more than a few seconds.
- This is not safe for a second.
- It is just as hard to balance
on a bike with locked steering
as it is to balance on a stationary bike.
- No, this one is impossible.
- Because you can't steer the bike
back under you.
The real reason bicycles are stable without riders
is because they're cleverly designed to steer themselves.
If they start falling to one side,
the handlebars turn in that direction
to steer the wheels back underneath them.
At least three mechanisms
are responsible for a bike's corrective steering.
The first is that due to the angle of the front fork,
the steering axis intersects the ground
in front of where the wheel touches the ground.
So, if the bike starts leaning to the left,
the force from the ground on the tire
turns the wheel to the left.
If the bike starts leaning right,
the force from the ground pushes the wheel to the right.
The front wheel of a bicycle is essentially a caster wheel,
like those you find on strollers or shopping carts.
Whichever way you drive them,
the wheel falls in line and rolls in the same direction.
The second reason for a bike's corrective steering
is that the center of mass
of the handlebars and front wheel
are located slightly in front of the steering axis.
So, when the bike leans left,
their weight pushes the front wheel to the left.
If the bike leans right, their weight steers to the right.
And the third mechanism is a gyroscopic effect
but it doesn't keep the bike upright directly;
it just helps steer.
If you have a gyroscope
and you push down on the left-hand side,
the gyro will turn left.
If you push down on the right side, it will turn right.
This is known as gyroscopic precession.
It seems as though the force you apply
takes effect 90 degrees from where you applied it.
So, bikes are stable primarily because of steering.
They have built-in mechanisms for steering themselves.
In fact, you don't need all three mechanisms
to create a stable bike.
Researchers created this weird-looking bicycle
to prove a point.
It has no gyroscopic effect
thanks to counter-rotating wheels
above the wheels that touch the floor.
Plus, there is no caster effect
because the front wheel touches the floor
in front of the steering axis.
But this bike is made stable by its mass distribution,
the force of gravity on which
steers it in the direction of any lean.
Understanding how bicycles work
is still an active area of research.
There is a program you can use to input
all the different bicycle parameters
and see the range of speeds over which it is self-stable.
And this research is leading to better bikes.
This prototype has a smart motor in the handlebars
to actively help steer,
keeping the bike upright even at low speeds.
I guess it's fitting that we are still
learning new things about bicycles
since most of us are able to ride one
without any knowledge of how we're actually doing it.